A Guide to the Webb-Prentis Family Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Webb-Prentis Family Papers 1735-1942
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
4136-d
ca. 1300 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1989 May 23
Scope and Content
The collection contains sixteen cased daguerreotypes and ambrotypes; fifty-two cartes-de-visite, cabinet cards, and postcards; and one tintype. Among those depicted are Robert Riddick Prentis, Robert Henning Webb, and Richard Thomas Walker Duke, Jr.
Container Listing
- Photographs of the Webb, Prentis, and Riddick Families
  - Positive Paper Prints
    - George Lloyd Barton (see Charles Henry Causey ), n.d.; cabinet card
    - Annie Bernard, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Miss Bibb (see Misses Sharp, Southall, and Bibb), carte-de-visite
    - William Briggs, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Charles Henry Causey and George Lloyd Barton, cabinet card
    - G. Bowdoin Craighill, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Georgia C. Crump, n.d.; cabinet card
    - J. Lawrence Daniel (see Richard McGehee. ..), n.d.; 5 3/4" x 4 3/4"
    - Mary Darden, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Richard Thomas Walker Duke, Jr., n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - James C. Eley (see Richard McGehee. ..), n.d.; 5 3/4" x 4 3/4"
    - Mrs. Walker B. Ferguson, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Robert E. Fultz, 1901; 4 1/2" x 6"
    - Anna Belle F[ ], 1902; 4 1/4" x 6 1/2"
    - Robert Hall, n.d.; cabinet card
    - J. E. B. Halladay, 1900; 3 7/8" x 5 3/8"
    - Thomas Sanford Hart, 1900; 4" x 5 3/4"
    - Thomas Bernard Jones, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - Miss [ ] Jones, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - George G. Junkin (see Richard McGehee. ..), n.d.; 5 3/4" x 4 3/4"
    - John Richardson Kilby, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - Wilbur J. Kilby, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - Wilbur J. Kilby, 1875; carte-de-visite
    - Wilbur J. Kilby, 1898; 6 3/4" x 9"
    - Richard McGehee; George G. Junkin; John B. McFerrin; James C. Eley; J. Lawrence Daniel, n.d.; 5 3/4" x 4 3/4"
    - John B. McFerrin (see Richard McGehee. ..), n.d.; 5 3/4" x 4 3/4"
    - Harris Moss, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Effie Murray, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Helen Murray, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Wallace Murray (right), n.d.; cabinet card
    - Wallace Murray, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Mrs. William W. Murray, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Allie Murrell, n.d.; 6" x 8"
    - C. B. [Nelson?], 1900; 5 1/4" x 7 1/4"
    - Janet W. Prentis, 1887-1888; cabinet card
    - Robert Riddick Prentis (2 copies), n.d.; cabinet card
    - Robert Riddick Prentis, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Robert Riddick Prentis (3 copies), n.d.; 5 1/4" x 7 3/8"
    - Robert Riddick Prentis, 1904; 5 7/8" x 7 7/8"
    - Robert Riddick Prentis, n.d.; 7" x 9"
    - M. Raine, n.d.; 2 1/8" x 2 3/4"
    - Mrs. Joseph Riddick, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Misses Sharp, Southall and Bibb, carte-de-visite
    - Miss Southall (see Misses Sharp, Southall and Bibb), carte-de-visite
    - [Happer?] Stewart and Mrs. William H. Stewart, 7 1/4" x 5 1/8"
    - W. Carroll Vaden, n.d.; cabinet card
    - Dr. Vandersliee, cabinet card
    - Robert Henning Webb (left, balloon), 1907; postcard
    - Robert Henning Webb (left, front of house), n.d.; 5 1/2" x 5 1/2"
    - Janet Whitehead, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - Margaret G. Whitehead, 1894; cabinet card
    - S. B. Woods, n.d.; carte-de-visite
    - unidentified woman, 1907; postcard
    - unidentified woman, 1896; cabinet card
    - unidentified woman (Newman), 1912; 4" x 7"
    - unidentified man (name Mary Darden written on back), n.d.; cabinet card
    - unidentified group of two women and two men, tintype
  - Cased Photographs
    - Rev. Allen Rodney Bernard, 1795-1866, husband of Lucy Swepson, daughter of Thomas Swepson and Anne (Riddick) Swepson, daguerrotype
    - John Robert Darden, 1841-1919, son of Mills William Darden and Sarah Jane (White) Darden (second wife), ambrotype
    - Algernon Sidney Darden and Mary Swepson (Allen) Darden, married November 27, 1853, daguerreotype
    - Indiana Virginia (Kilby) Henry, wife of Capt. Edward Moore Henry of Norfolk, and daughter of John Thompson Kilby and Ann Newton (Jones) Kilby, ambrotype
    - Mary Louisa (Darden) Pruden, born 1827, daughter of Mills William Darden and Ann Missouri (Jordan) Darden. Married Nathaniel E. Pruden of Spring Hill, Nansemond County, daguerreotype
    - Rev. Joseph Henry Riddick, n.d.; daguerreotype
    - Mariana (Prentis) Riddick, wife of Richard Riddick, and daughter of Joseph Prentis II and Susan Caroline (Riddick) Prentis, ambrotype
    - Richard H. Riddick, n.d.; ambrotype
    - Walter Riddick, only child of Richard H. Riddick, Jr. and Marianna Saunders (Prentis) Riddick. Drowned in childhood., daguerreotype
    - Walter Riddick, n.d.; ambrotype
    - Mary Diana (Webb) Upshaw, 1830-1903, wife of Col. Thomas Edmund Upshaw, and daughter of Col. Richard Daniel Webb and Mary Allen (Riddick) Webb, daguerreotype
    - Margaret Susan (Prentis) Webb, 1810-1882, wife of Robert Henning Webb, and daughter of Joseph Prentis and Susan Caroline (Riddick) Prentis, daguerreotype
    - Robert Henning Webb, n.d.; ambrotype
    - Robert Henning Webb (2 cases), n.d.; daguerreotype
    - Eliza Ann (Swepson) Whitlock, 1798-1866, wife of James Whitlock, and daughter of Thomas Swepson and Charlotte (Driver) Swepson, daguerreotype